Muhammad Syafiq Bin Saidan

BANDAR BARU UDA, JOHOR BAHRU, JOHOR - MALAYSIA

Resume Summary

Current Position Senior Officer in Hitachi Koki (Malaysia) Sdn Bhd

(March 2011 - Present)

Current Specialization Administration & Human Resources Highest Education Diploma in Engineering (Mechanical)

Working Experience 6 years (including brief employment at Japan)

Expected Salary MYR 5000 (gross, negotiable)

Employment History

March 2011 - Present

1. Hitachi Koki (Malaysia) Sdn Bhd

Position Title (Level) Senior Officer (Senior Executive)
Specialization Administration & Human Resources
Role General HR & Translator / Interpreter

Industry Manufacturing / Production

Monthly Salary MYR 3800

Work Description

Responsibilities

- ◆ Handle translation and interpretation work for administration and production department (Japanese, English, Malay);
- ◆ Handle company secretarial work and work closely with company secretary, company auditor and company tax consultant;
- ◆ Involved in the promotion and implementation of 5S project;
- ◆ Administer company transportation for employees:
- Administer work pass application, renewal & cancellations for expatriate staffs;
- ◆ Liaise and work closely with expatriate on staff welfare and benefits;
- ◆ Administer medical and other fringe benefits claim application from employees;
- ◆ Organize and administer annual health screening for company employees;
- ♦ Handle insurance claims and work closely with insurance brokers;
- ◆ Manage and procure office equipment repairs and maintenance, office supplies and company uniforms;

Experience and Knowledge gained

- ◆ Experience and Knowledge in industrial relation staff welfare and benefit, collective agreement structure and contents, employee insurance, etc.
- ◆ Experience in SOP and/or WIS translation work; simultaneous interpretation in video conference, Board of Directors' meeting, and Annual General Meeting. Utilize computer aided translation (CAT) software in translation work.
- ◆ Experience in liaising and managing expatriate staffs (Japanese) employment package contract, expatriate welfare and benefits, taxation matters, etc.
- ◆ Knowledge in Human Resources issues Minimum Wage Act implementation and subsequent collective agreement negotiation, Foreign Workers hiring and management, Minimum Retirement Age Act implementation and management, Employees training and education management, Payroll management, etc.

Achievement

◆ Improved office supplies and company uniform inventory management by using spreadsheets - cut required man-hours to execute tasks by about 50% and reduced inventory by 20%;

Curriculum Vitae

- ◆ Improved claim monitoring procedures by using spreadsheets cut required claims processing task man-hours by about 50% and improved over-claim and false claim detection mechanism.
- ◆ Improved communication between Japanese expatriates and local staffs help bridge language and culture barriers, facilitating active and more accurate communication between top management and all level of staffs.

Sep 2007 - Feb 2011

2.UMIDA Industries Sdn. Bhd.

Position Title (Level) Business Owner cum Manager

Specialization Publishing/Printing Role Publishing/Printing

Industry Printing / Publishing

Monthly Salary MYR 2000

Work Description

Responsibilities

- ◆ Take the lead role in marketing and selling print media and packaging products/services to prospective organization and individual clients.
- ◆ Responsibility for business development and sales process from initial point of contact (lead generation), presentations, proposals, through contract negotiations and execution.
- ◆ Work closely with the operational teams and outsourcing partners, utilize relationships to ensure that product implementation schedules are met.
- ◆ Facilitate strategic partners' resources for order fulfillment from sales to delivery, artwork design to printing, marketing and after-sales service.
- ◆ Supervise company accounts and finance management.

Experience and Knowledge gained

- ◆ Experience in business development and marketing / selling services for print media and packaging products/services; from artwork design phase to after-sales service.
- ◆ Experience in doing management and administrative work; payroll processing, staff welfare and benefits management, employee recruitment, retention and retrenchment, company secretarial matters, etc.
- ◆ Experience in negotiating with stakeholders (suppliers, employees, banks, etc) in order to get their support and approval for company winding up.
- ◆ Skills and knowledge in utilizing the internet for resource and information gathering for problem solving, software applications (Microsoft Office, Sage UBS, Adobe Photoshop / Illustrator, CorelDraw, etc.)

Achievement

- ◆ Obtained bridge financing from various internal and external resources in order to improve cash flow and balance sheet.
- ◆ Developed and launched various new innovative products / services. Learned crucial lessons about product marketing and management from failure of products.
- ◆ Analyzed and identified the main factors of family business crisis. Gained stakeholders' support and consensus on company winding up after thorough discussion with other shareholders (family members and friends), and consultation with experts.

Reason for leaving

Dissolve family business of 14 years to cut loss and mitigate impact on family finance.

Apr 2007 - Sep 2007

3. Fullcast Technology Co., Ltd

Position Title (Level) Assistant Engineer (Fresh / Entry Level)

Specialization Engineering - Electrical

Role Start-up / Testing and Commissioning

Curriculum Vitae

Industry Process and Factory Automation Consulting & Service Provider

(IT, Science, Engineering & Technical)

Monthly Salary JPY 185000

Work Description

Responsibilities

- ◆ Assigned to Yokogawa Electric Corporation as Start-up / Testing and Commissioning Assistant Engineer.
- ♦ Work in group for startup / testing and commissioning of Process/Factory Automation and Control, Test and Measurement devices and instruments.

Experience and Knowledge gained

- ◆ Experience and knowledge of industrial / factory automation process.
- ◆ Experience in working in an industry that requires meticulous attention to details and teamwork among members with background from diverse race and nationalities.

Reason for leaving

Returned to Malaysia to help solve family business crisis.

• Educational Background

Graduation Date 2007

Qualification Diploma of Engineering (Mechanical)
Major Mechanical Engineering (Fluid Dynamics)
Institute/University Tokyo National College of Technology, Japan

Grade B/2nd Class Upper

Certification

| Malaysian University English Test - Band 4 (Score - 215) | (2012) |
|--|--------|
| Japanese Language Proficiency Test Level 1 | (2010) |
| TOEIC (Score - 980) | (2007) |

Skills

(Proficiency: Advanced - Highly experienced; Intermediate - Familiar with all the basic functionalities; Beginner - Just started using or learning the skill)

| <u>Skill</u> | <u>Years</u> | <u>Proficiency</u> |
|------------------|--------------|--------------------|
| Microsoft Office | >5 | Intermediate |
| SDL Trados | 1 | Beginner |
| Sage UBS | 1 | Beginner |

Languages

(Proficiency: 0=Poor - 10=Excellent)

| <u>Language</u> | <u>Spoken</u> | <u>Written</u> |
|-----------------|---------------|----------------|
| Bahasa Malaysia | 10 | 9 |
| Japanese | 8 | 7 |
| English | 8 | 9 |

Personal Particulars & Preferences

Date of Birth 3 Jan 1984 Nationality Malaysia Gender Male

IC No. 840103-01-5849

Possess Own Transport Yes

Expected Monthly Salary MYR 5000 (gross, negotiable)

Availability Immediately after notice period of 6 weeks

Curriculum Vitae

Additional Info

Career Objective

Contribute to company bottom line by utilizing experience and knowledge as an Interpreter / Translator and HR Practitioner in reducing and bridging the gap between the management and other staffs. Gain experience and knowledge in Business Finance and Accountings during tenure in order to further own growth and self-development.

Interest

Have deep interest in finance and economics (currently applying to further study for Bachelor Degree in Finance (part time) at a local government university). Passionate reader and love travelling.

Training experience

- ♦ ISO 14000:01 EMS Internal Auditor
- ◆ Finance for non-finance personnel

Summary

- ◆ Possess vast knowledge and experience in company secretarial, administrative, accounting, and human resources related matters.
- ◆ Possess great communication skills and leadership attributions, a people person.
- ◆ Passionate and diligent in work, a good team player and capable of multitasking.
- ◆ Proven self- initiative and ability to work with minimal supervision.
- ◆ Excellent organizational and motivational skills.
- ◆ Possess good business acumen, a fast learner and resourceful.

References

Name Prof. Saito Sumio

Relationship Lecturer / Thesis Advisor

Position Professor, Department of Mechanical Engineering

Company Tokyo National College of Technology

Telephone +81426685161 Email saito@tokyo-ct.ac.jp

Name Oovama Masavuki

Relationship Superior (Part time language teacher)
Position Branch Manager, Johor Bahru School
Company AtoZ Language Centre Sdn Bhd

Telephone +60123139878

Email <u>ooyama@atozlanguage.com</u>

Name Haikal Hashron

Relationship Ex-business partner & colleague

Position Sales Executive Company HSBC Berhad +60127014499

Email <u>haikal.hashron@gmail.com</u>

Name Ridzuan Siam Relationship Colleague

Position Training Officer / HR Generalist Company Hitachi Koki (Malaysia) Sdn Bhd

Telephone +60197258575

Email ridzuanhrd@yahoo.com